Phoebe found out about this lady...
我们跑去海边 因为菲比找到一个女人
...who knew her parents, and I don't know what happened.
她认识她的父母 然后我就不知道了
I'm your mother.
我是你的母亲
Monica joked she wouldn't date Chandler.
摩妮卡开玩笑说 她不会跟钱德这种人约会
I don't know what happened there either.
他一直很在意 然后我也不知道了
Ross' new girlfriend shows up.
罗斯的新女朋友邦妮跑来
Rachel gets Bonnie to shave her head. Then they kiss.
瑞秋说服她理了个大光头 然后罗斯和瑞秋接吻了
Now he has to choose Rachel or the bald girl.
现在他得在瑞秋 和光头女之间二选一
I don't know what happened there either.
然后我还是不知道
Hold on. Let me go get Chandler.
等一下，我去找钱德来
She's helping me. My head's sunburned.
她在帮我搽药，我的头晒伤了
-Thanks a million. -You're welcome a million.
感激不尽 不用客气
Smell it.
你闻
Minty.
凉凉的
I'll be in our room.
我先回房去
Oh,my God!
天哪
I know.
我知道
I got to go.
好，我走了
Why?
什么？为什么？
I got to go break up with Bonnie.
我得跟邦妮分手
Here? Now?
在这里？现在？
I can't stay here all night.
我不能整晚留在这里
If I go in there,she'll want to...
要是我回房，她会想…
...do stuff.
嘿咻
Can't you say you aren't in the mood?
你不能说你没心情吗？
No,she likes that.
她喜欢那样
Faking sleep doesn't work.
装睡也没用
I've woken up many times with her
我经常早上醒来发现她在…
好
-Why am I telling you? -I don't know.
我说这个干什么？ 我不知道
-Not every morning -Making it worse!
并不是每天早上都… 再描会更黑
The One with the Jellyfish
本集播出：“前缘难续”
rainystar压制iPod-MP4
You probably want to know how it happened.
你大概想知道前因后果
I think I can figure it out.
我猜想得到
I was born,and then everyone lied their asses off.
我出生之后 大家开始卯起来撒谎
No,it wasn't like that.
不是那样的
Remember how I said Lilly,Frank and I were close?
我不是说过 莉莉、法兰克和我很要好？
We were very close.
我们非常要好
How close?
怎么说？
The three of us were kind of a couple.
我们三个是一对
I don't know how that would work.
三个怎么会是一对
I'm not asking!
我们… 我不是在问你
Anyhow,somehow I got pregnant...
总之，我不知怎的怀孕了
...and I was...
我很…
...scared. I was stupid and selfish....
…害怕，我愚昧又自私…
I was 18 years old. Remember what it was like to be 18?
我才18岁 还记得你的18岁吗？
Mom killed herself and my dad ran off.
记得，妈自杀，爸跑掉
I lived in a Gremlin with a guy who talked to his hand.
我跟一个叫山迪的人住在一起 他会跟他的手说话
I'm sorry. I thought I'd left you with the best parents.
对不起 我以为他们是世上最好的父母
I didn't hear about them till a few years ago.
直到几年前 我才听说他们的事
By then,you were already grown-up.
当时你已经长大了
You're here and I would really like to get to know you.
既然你来了，我也想多认识你
Well,everybody does.
每个人都想认识我
I'm a really cool person.
我是个很酷的人
You had 29 years to find out, but you didn't even try.
你有29年的时间可以查 却连试都没试
You walked out on me, and I'll do the same.
你扔下我不管，现在我也要
I don't ever want to see you again.
等一下
我不想再见到你
Where's my purse?
我的皮包呢？
Shoot! We're out of soda.
讨厌，没有汽水了
-I'll get you some. -Really?
我去帮你买 真的？
No,because I'm not your boyfriend.
才怪，我又不是你的男朋友
Hey,Pheebs,how'd it go?
菲比，怎么样？
My mom's friend,Phoebe, is actually my birth mom.
我妈的朋友菲比 其实是我的亲生母亲
I found a dried-up seahorse.
我检到一个干掉的海马
What do you mean?
什么意思？
My new mom, who's a big fat abandoner.
我的新妈妈当年抛弃了我
Don't you want to stay here and talk about it?
菲比，等等 你不坐下来聊一聊吗？
I need to be alone.
不了，我想静一静
摩妮卡
Man. Hey...
...what if you found out that your mom wasn't really your mom...
要是你发现你妈不是你妈
...and your new mom turned out to be really hot?
而你的新妈妈又很辣呢？
Oh,man,huh?
But,it's your mom.
但她是你妈耶
No,I'm talking about your mom.
不，我是在说你妈
It's over.
结束了
Was it awful?
很惨吗？
It was long.
很久
I didn't realize how late it was...
我没意识到那么晚了
...till I saw the five o'clock shadow on her head.
直到她头上出现5点钟的日影
She didn't want to stay. I called a cab. She just left.
她不想留下来 我帮她叫了车，她刚走
I wrote you a letter.
我写了封信给你
Oh,thank you!
谢谢
I like mail.
我喜欢收信
It's just some things I've been thinking about. About us.
我想了一些关于我们的事
Before we even think about us getting back together...
在我们考虑复合之前
...I need to know how you feel about this stuff.
我得知道你对这封信的想法
好
It's 5:30 in the morning.
现在是早上5点半
So I'd better get cracking on this baby.
我最好赶快看完
I'll be waiting for you. Come up when you're done.
我等你，看完就上来
I'll be up...
好，我要花…
...in 18 pages.
十八页的时间
Front and back.
从头到尾
Very exciting!
好兴奋喔
What happened to you? Why didn't you come up?
怎么了？你怎么没上来？
Done.
看完了
-You just finished? -I wanted to be thorough.
你才刚看完？ 我想看仔细一点
This is clearly very important to you. To us.
这对你…对我们显然很重要
I wanted to read every word carefully.
我想一字一句用心斟酌
Twice.
斟酌两次
Does it?
所以…行吗？
I'm sorry?
什么？
Does it?
行吗？
Does it? Does it?
行吗？行吗？
I wanted to give that whole "Does it?" part another glance.
我想再瞄一眼“行吗”的部份
What do you mean? You said you read it twice.
什么意思？你说你看了两次
It either does or doesn't. If you have to think
行不行一句话 如果你还要考虑…
No,I don't have to think about it.
不，我不用考虑，不用
In fact...
事实上…
...I've decided. I have decided...
我已经决定了，我决定…
...that it...
这件事…
...does.
行
-Are you sure? -Sure,I'm sure!
你确定？ 确定
There's a nuclear holocaust. I'm the last man on earth.
好，发生核爆灾难 我是世上仅存的男人
Would you go out with me?
你会跟我约会吗？
I've got canned goods.
我有罐头喔
Take a look at this!
喂，你们看
Check this baby out! Dug me a hole.
你们瞧瞧，我挖了个洞
Excellent hole,Joe.
好棒的洞啊
Oh,no! My hole!
不！我的洞！
My foot!
我的脚！
What is it?
怎么了？
Jellyfish sting! It hurts!
我被水母咬了，好痛…
Can we help you to the house?
要不要扶你回去？
It's two miles.
2哩耶
And I'm tired from digging.
而且我挖洞挖得好累
Damn the jellyfish!
该死的水母
Damn all the jellyfish!
所有的水母都去死
Do something.
得想个办法
There's only one thing.
只有一个办法
What is it?
什么办法？
Pee on it.
在伤口上撒尿
Gross!
什么？好恶！
I saw it on Discovery Channel.
别怪我 我是在探索频道上看到的
He's right. There's ammonia in that...
他没唬你，尿液里有氨
...that kills the pain.
可以止痛
Forget it. It doesn't hurt that bad!
我不要，其实没那么痛…
You can use my hole for privacy.
你可以躲进我的洞里
I'm ready to get the hell out of here.
我准备好要走了
Are you?
你们…？真的？
That's so great!
太棒了
Not for Bonnie.
邦妮好可怜
But for you,yea!
但恭喜你们了
-How was the beach? -Nothing. I don't know.
海边好玩吗？ 不怎么样，我不知道
-What happened? -Nothing.
怎么了？ 没事
-I'm going to shower. -Me too.
我要去冲澡 我也是
Me too.
我也是
I'll put this in the car.
我把袋子拿到车上
I have to go pack!
我得去收东西
-And it really does? -lt does.
真的行吗？ 行
It really and truly does.
真的真的行
It so does not!
行你个头！
（中央咖啡馆）
She wants me to take responsibility for everything that went wrong.
她要我对我们的失和 负起全部的责任
She goes on for five pages about how I was unfaithful to her.
她写了整整五页 说我如何不忠
We were on a break!
我们当时分手了
If you say that one more time, I'll break up with you.
天哪，你再说一次 我就跟你分手
This breakup was not all my fault. She says here...
分手不是我一个人的错 她写说
..."lf you accept full responsibility...
“要是你负起全部的责任”
...I can begin to trust you again.
“我就能再次信任你”
Does that seem like something you can do? Does it?"
“你想你办得到吗？行吗？”
不行
You have what you want. You're back with her.
你得偿所愿，跟她复合了
If you bring this up now, you'll wreck it.
现在提出来 会毁了你一生中最美好的事
Yeah,I know. You're right.
我知道，你说得对
I'll let it go.
我会就此打住
But you know how hard it is to forget this?
但你们了解这件事很难忘记吧
Sure,it's hard...
当然很难
...but you don't have to talk about it.
但你不必拿出来谈
A lot happened on that trip...
这次度假有很多事
...that we should never,ever talk about.
都该从此绝口不提
What happened on that beach?
在海边到底怎么了？
It's between us and the sea,Ross.
那是我们和大海的秘密
Hi,Ursula.
乌苏拉
I know that we haven't talked in a long time.
我知道我们很久没联络了
Our mom is not our birth mom. This other lady is our birth mom.
但我们的妈妈不是亲妈妈 另一个女的才是
Right,the one that lives in Montauk.
对，住在莫陶克的那个
You know her?
你认识她？
No. I read about her in Mom's suicide note.
不认识，但妈的遗书里有提到
There was a suicide note? Do you still have it?
妈有留遗书？还在吗？
Hang on.
等一下
I can't believe you didn't tell me there was a suicide note.
你居然没告诉我有遗书
Yeah,so how have you been doing?
是啊，你最近好吗？
Shut up!
我…闭嘴
"Goodbye,Phoebe and Ursula. I'll miss you.
“别了，菲比与乌苏拉” “我会想念你们”
P.S. Your mom lives in Montauk."
“又：你们母亲住在莫陶克”
You just wrote this!
这是你刚才写的
It's pretty much the gist.
差不多是这个意思
Except for the poem. You read the poem,right?
只差那首诗，你读过那首诗吧
没有
All right. Hang on.
等一下
Pass the cheese,please.
请把起司给我
You can't even look at me,can you?
你连看都不敢看我，对吧？
对
It's Phoebe! We can talk to Phoebe!
是菲比！我们可以跟菲比说话
I'm too depressed to talk.
我很沮丧，不想说话
I'll give you $1000 to talk to us.
我给你1千元开口费
What about making that beach trip an annual thing?
我们要不要每年都回去玩？
不要
What happened out there?
够了，到底出了什么事？
What? We took a walk. Nothing happened.
什么？ 我们只是去散步，没什么
I came back with nothing all over me.
我身上什么都没沾到
What happened? Joey?
拜托，到底是…乔伊？
All right.
好吧 不行
We swore we'd never tell.
我们发誓要死守秘密
They'll never understand.
他们不会了解的
We have to get it out. It's eating me alive!
我们得说出来，我快被逼疯了
-Monica got stung by a jellyfish. -All right!
摩妮卡被水母咬到 好吧
好吧
I got stung.
我被咬到
Stung bad.
咬得很严重
I couldn't stand.
站都站不直
I couldn't walk.
走也走不动
We were two miles from the house.
我们离小屋2哩远
We were scared and alone.
既孤单又害怕
We didn't think we could make it.
我们还以为死定了
I was in too much pain.
我痛得要命
And I was tired from digging.
我刚挖完洞好累
Then Joey remembered something.
然后乔伊想起一件事
I'd seen it on Discovery Channel.
是在探索频道上看到的
Wait,I saw that.
慢着，我也看过
On the Discovery Channel. About jellyfish and how if you
是探索频道没错 它说要是你被水母…
You peed on yourself?
你在自己身上撒尿？
You can't say that! You don't know!
你不能这么说！你不知道
I thought I would pass out.
我都快痛昏了
I tried,but I couldn't...
我试过，但没办法…
...bend that way.
弯成那个姿势
所以…
That's right. I stepped up.
没错，我挺身而出
She's my friend and she needed help.
她是我的朋友，她需要帮助
If I had to, I'd pee on any of you.
如果有必要 我也会在你们身上撒尿
Only...
只不过…
...I couldn't.
我尿不出来
I got the stage fright.
我怯场了
I wanted to help, but there was too much pressure.
我很想帮忙，但压力太大了
So I turned to Chandler.
所以我找钱德
Joey kept screaming at me, "Do it now. Do it. Do it now!"
乔伊一直对我大叫 “快尿！快点尿！”
Sometimes,late at night, I can still hear the screaming.
有时在深夜里 我还会听到那个叫声
Because I do it through my wall to freak you out.
那是我在隔壁吓你
Maybe there's somebody you guys could talk to.
也许你们可以找人谈谈
Oh,who?
找谁？
It's not like they have a group for people like us.
难道这种事还有团体治疗？
Yeah,no,there's this guy Owen,he's the best.
有个叫欧文的很厉害
Might have his card.
我有他的名片
And fuchsia and mauve
还有紫红色和淡紫色
Those are the 66 colors of my bedroom
这就是我房里的六十六种颜色
I invite all of you to count the colors in your bedroom.
大家都回去算算房里的颜色吧
Except for you. You go away.
你除外，你给我滚
I'll go in a second.
我马上就走
I just want to tell you...
我只想告诉你
...there wasn't a day I didn't regret giving you up.
我每天都在后悔把你送人
Okay,bye.
好，再见
I'm not done.
我还没说完
The reason I never looked you up was because...
我之所以没找过你是因为…
...I was afraid you'd react...
我很怕你的反应
...just like the way you're reacting now.
会跟现在一样
Can't we just start from here? Please?
我们不能从现在开始吗？
No.
不行
好吧
Sorry.
抱歉
One last thing.
最后一件事
You came looking for family.
你来找你的家人
I'm family.
我就是了
I'm it.
没别人了
Now I'm done.
我说完了
It's not like we're losing anything.
我们又没什么损失
I guess you're right.
你说得对
It's not like we know each other or have anything in common.
我们又不熟 也没什么共同点
I don't know. It's not like...
我不晓得，我们不见得…
...we don't have anything in common.
没有共同点
I mean,I like pizza.
像我喜欢披萨
I like pizza!
我也喜欢披萨
Wait,I like the Beatles.
是吗？等等，我喜欢披头四
Oh,my God! So do l.
天哪，我也是
Puppies. Cute or ugly?
等等，小狗狗可不可爱？
So cute!
可爱死了
You see?
看吧
But I'm still mad at you.
但我还是很气你
I know.
我知道
I'm mad at me too.
我也很气自己
Do you want to get something to eat? I'm kind of hungry.
你想吃东西吗？我有点饿
Hey! Me too!
我也是
Uncanny.
太不可思议了
It looks like rain and I don't have my umbrella.
好像快下雨了，我没带伞
Me neither. I really hate that.
我也是，真讨厌
Stop it. Now you're just doing it to freak me out.
够了，你现在只是想吓我
I missed you.
我好想你
I missed you too.
我也很想你
I was so nervous about that letter.
我对那封信好紧张
But the way you owned up to everything...
但是你这么坦然认错
...it just showed me how much you've grown.
证明你真的成长不少
I suppose.
大概吧
You have,Ross. You should give yourself credit.
你有，罗斯，你不该妄自菲薄
My mom never thought this would work out.
我妈一直觉得我们无法复合
She said,"Once a cheater, always a cheater."
她说：出轨是不可原谅的
I just wish we hadn't lost those four months.
真希望没有这4个月的空白
But if time was what you needed to gain a little perspective....
但要是时间能让你看清楚一点
We were on a break!
我们当时分手了！
-Coffeehouse? -You bet.
喝咖啡？ 好
It took two people to break up this relationship.
这段感情会破裂是两个人的错
You and that girl, which yesterday you took full responsibility for.
对，你和影印店那个女的 你昨天表明愿意负责
I didn't know what I took responsibility for.
我不知道我负的是什么责
I didn't finish the letter.
我没把信看完 什么？
I fell asleep.
我睡着了
You fell asleep?
你睡着了？
It was 5:30 in the morning.
当时是早上5点半
And you had rambled on for 18 pages.
你一废话就废话了十八页
Front and back!
从头到尾
By the way,Y-O-U-apostrophe-R-E means "you are."
还有 “you're”是指“you are”
Y-O-U-R means "your."
“Y-O-U-R”是代表your
I can't believe I thought of getting back with you! We are so over.
我居然会想跟你复合 我们根本就完了
Fine by me!
无所谓
Those spelling tips will be handy Saturday nights at home...
你星期六晚上 跟摩妮卡玩拼字游戏时
...playing Scrabble with Monica.
一定不会写错字
Sorry!
对不起
All that sleep you'll miss wishing you were with me!
我只可怜你会想我想到失眠
Don't worry about me falling asleep.
别怕我会睡不着
I still have your letter!
我还有你的信
Just so you know, it's not that common.
顺便告诉你 这种事并不常见
It doesn't happen to every guy.
并非男人都会这样
And it is a big deal!
这是很严重的
I knew it!
我就知道
Gin.
我赢了
We were playing gin?
我们在玩金罗美牌？
If we were a couple, we could play naked.
如果我们是一对，就可以光着身体玩了
-Would you stop? -Okay. All right.
别再说了 好吧
All right.
好啦
I think you're great.
我觉得你很棒
I think you're sweet and smart...
我觉得你人很好，很聪明
...and I love you.
我爱你
But you'll always be the guy who peed on me.
但你永远是在我身上撒尿的人